<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Simon Perdrisat</title><link>http://perdrisat.com/</link><description>Recent content on Simon Perdrisat</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>perdrisat@gmail.com (Simon Perdrisat)</managingEditor><webMaster>perdrisat@gmail.com (Simon Perdrisat)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 21:00:58 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://perdrisat.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Case study of sociotechnical imaginaries in the making: kleros decentralized dispute resolution protocol</title><link>http://perdrisat.com/post/case_study_of_sociotechnical_imaginaries_in_the_making/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 21:00:58 +0100</pubDate><author>perdrisat@gmail.com (Simon Perdrisat)</author><guid>http://perdrisat.com/post/case_study_of_sociotechnical_imaginaries_in_the_making/</guid><description>Abstract In the current context of growing uncertainty about the future, researchers began investigating how future visions shape the present; how sociotechnical imaginaries actively shape our society. Today, the performativity of imagined futures is well understood. However, how particular visions come about and why they become performative is understudied. Using the theoretical framework of “technique of futuring” and “dramaturgical regimes”, this case study analyzes how Kleros stakeholders articulated and communicate discourse about the Kleros technology’s potentialities to better understand how imaginaries emerge.</description></item><item><title>Blockchain, A New Socio-Technical Environment (OpenAccess Book)</title><link>http://perdrisat.com/post/blockchain-a-new-socio-technical-environment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 18:43:53 +0100</pubDate><author>perdrisat@gmail.com (Simon Perdrisat)</author><guid>http://perdrisat.com/post/blockchain-a-new-socio-technical-environment/</guid><description>Book published!!!
Blockchain is widely considered a new key technology. This study examines how blockchain became mainstream and provides the much-needed social contextualisation of blockchain. It explores the origins of blockchain in the early history of information technology and computer networks. The study also reveals the impact blockchain has on industrial and public spaces. Finally, it discusses the social implications and challenges of blockchain against the background of a new socio-technical environment.</description></item><item><title>Political motivations and technical objects: Understanding the participation of developers in the Bitcoin project</title><link>http://perdrisat.com/post/understanding_the_participation_of_developers_in_the_bitcoin_project/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 18:43:53 +0100</pubDate><author>perdrisat@gmail.com (Simon Perdrisat)</author><guid>http://perdrisat.com/post/understanding_the_participation_of_developers_in_the_bitcoin_project/</guid><description>This work seeks to know whether political motivations are at the origin of the actors&amp;rsquo; involvement in an information technology project, Bitcoin.
We will study the motivations of the developers who participated in the development of the Bitcoin open source software source code. Bitcoin is an electronic currency that can be exchanged over the Internet, the first version of which was published in 2009.
This work will address the following elements.</description></item><item><title>Les effets imprévus de la diplomatie américaine dans le cadre du congrès pour la liberté de la culture</title><link>http://perdrisat.com/post/les-effets-imprevus-de-la-diplomatie-americaine/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 21:00:58 +0100</pubDate><author>perdrisat@gmail.com (Simon Perdrisat)</author><guid>http://perdrisat.com/post/les-effets-imprevus-de-la-diplomatie-americaine/</guid><description>La diplomatie culturelle peut avoir des conséquences inattendues. Ce travail s&amp;rsquo;intéresse ici aux circulations des idées et aux divergences entre l&amp;rsquo;Europe et les USA dans le cadre du Congrès pour la liberté de la culture. Ce congrès est considéré aujourd’hui par un historien de la CIA comme une des opérations de la guerre froide les plus audacieuses et efficace.
Full paper (open-access): https://doi.org/10.31235/osf.io/m72ng</description></item><item><title>First Class Rail in Switzerland: The effect of a two-tier ticket structure on energy use</title><link>http://perdrisat.com/post/first-class-rail-in-switzerland-the-effect-on-energy-use/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 17:16:34 +0100</pubDate><author>perdrisat@gmail.com (Simon Perdrisat)</author><guid>http://perdrisat.com/post/first-class-rail-in-switzerland-the-effect-on-energy-use/</guid><description>This paper explores whether SBB can spare energy by renouncing its first class. SBB currently offers two classes on intercity trains. A first-class ticket is twice the price of the second-class ticket for the same travel. The first-class passenger cars have a lower number of seats and potentially different occupancy. Through different scenarios, we will analyse how this difference in price and seat density between the first and second classes can affect the energy consumption by people transported on the intercity line between Zurich and Geneva.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>http://perdrisat.com/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>perdrisat@gmail.com (Simon Perdrisat)</author><guid>http://perdrisat.com/contact/</guid><description>perdrisat@gmail.com https://twitter.com/gagarine</description></item></channel></rss>